Organized crime has never been this disorganized!
Johnny Dangerously is a comedy, crime film directed by Amy Heckerling.
An honest, goodhearted man is forced to turn to a life of crime to
finance his neurotic mother's skyrocketing medical bills.
Johnny Dangerously, played by Michael Keaton.
Vermin, played by Joe Piscopo.
Lil, played by Marilu Henner.
Mom, played by Maureen Stapleton.
Dundee, played by Peter Boyle.
Tommy, played by Griffin Dunne.
Johnny Dangerously is a 1984 American crime comedy film directed by Amy Heckerling; two of its four
screenwriters, Jeff Harris and Bernie Kukoff, had previously created the hit series Diff'rent Strokes.
The film, a parody of 1930s crime/gangster movies, stars Michael Keaton as an honest, goodhearted man who turns to a life of
crime to finance his mother's skyrocketing medical bills and to put his younger brother through law school.
Joe Piscopo, Marilu Henner, Maureen Stapleton, Peter Boyle, Griffin Dunne,
Dom DeLuise, Danny DeVito, Dick Butkus and Alan Hale Jr.
were in the film.
Part of the film's comedic appeal is the frequent use of malapropisms by Johnny and other
crime characters, especially in instances where curse words were intended.
The film explores themes of mobster, organized crime, woman director, 1930s.
The tone is lighthearted.